Joonas Hiltunen

+358 44 9890011 | joonas@jontzi.com | joonashiltunen.fi | LinkedIn | GitHub

Profile

I am a versatile full-stack software developer with over five years of comprehensive experience in various projects, from small one-person apps to extensive enterprise software. I excel in C# and JS/TS-based projects while being flexible and quickly grasping new technologies as required. I am interested in taking on a more significant role in some larger projects and in expanding my expertise in cloud technologies.

Experience

Vincit Oyj

Mar. 2022 – Present

Software Developer

I am working as a software developer for a software and digital consultancy called Vincit. During my time at Vincit, I have been part of multiple projects across various industries using numerous technologies, demonstrating adaptability to different domains.

- I am currently working as a senior full-stack developer in a fast-paced hospitality project to create a new website, a custom booking engine and a new services website for a prominent Finnish hospitality chain.
 - o The new platform allows the aggregation of reservations from multiple channels, enabling significantly better customer profiling with the aggregated customer data.
 - o Initial results after release revealed up to a 100% conversion increase on mobile platforms.
 - o After the initial release, I led the development of administration software for the new booking engine.
- Developed an AI content generation bot MVP for a major e-sports organization, now being considered for productization by the customer.
 - O The bot considerably reduced the workload of the social team during matches of the organization's teams.
- Designed a unique reporting microservice for a leading Finnish B2B energy industry software company's SaaS product.
 - o The microservice significantly reduced the workload of monitoring a small-scale electric network.
- Prepared multiple components of another SaaS of the same energy industry company for expansion into foreign markets.
 - With support for the new foreign market, the company could potentially access new multi-million contracts.
- Contributed to enhancing the internal payroll tool used for salary calculations between projects.

NomiCam Oy (Now part of Amazon Ring) Software Developer, Sept. 2020 – Feb. 2022

Junior Software Developer, Sept. 2019 – Aug. 2020

Software Developer Trainee, May 2019 - Aug. 2019

May 2019 – Feb. 2022

I worked at a Finnish start-up called NomiCam for around three years and held multiple roles there deciding to leave for my current job when the company was sold to Amazon Ring.

- Implemented and maintained software for NomiCam's Dynamic HDR measurement system
 - O Allows for quick and easy HDR measurements of a camera to be taken
 - o The system was considerably cheaper to manufacture and quicker to measure than competing products at the time
- Developed improvements and plugins for Mobile Imaging Playground (MIP)
- Introduced a CI pipeline for MIP
 - o Remarkably improved the build stability
 - O Paved the way for a much quicker release process for the software
- Build a remote control for an industrial robot using .NET Core
- Wrote user documentation for MIP and its plugins

Technical Skills

Languages: C#, TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL (PostgreSQL), Java, C++
Frameworks: .NET Core, ASP.NET, React, Node.is, Next.is, Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes, Visual Studio, CI/CD, Jest, Storyblok CMS, GitHub Actions

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure, Vercel

Education

Tampere University

Sept. 2022 - May 2024

Master of Science in Technology Major: Software, Web, and Cloud

Thesis: Comparison of cloud platforms for hosting microservices

Grade: 4 (very good)

Tampere University / Tampere University of Technology

Aug. 2018 – Sept. 2022

Bachelor of Science in Technology Major: Software Engineering

Thesis: Adding continuous delivery to a legacy software

Languages skills

Finnish: Native Proficiency

English: Full Professional Proficiency Swedish: Elementary Proficiency French: Elementary Proficiency

Other Projects

Homepage | React, Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Vercel | joonashiltunen.fi

- A new personal website for myself
- Build using Next.js with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS
- Deployed using Vercel

Flight randomizer | React, Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Chakra UI, Vercel | flights.jontzi.com

- A simple tool for selecting a random flight from an airport
- Created using Next.js with TypeScript and Chakra UI library
- Utilises data from FlightRadar24 APIs for finding airports and flights
- Deployed using Vercel

Get a Room! | React, Node.js, TypeScript, MUI, Google Cloud, Docker | getaroom.vincit.com

- A progressive web app for booking a meeting room on the fly
- Developed as part of a university course as part of a team
- Utilises Google Workspace and Google Calendar APIs
- Explicitly designed for Vincit but can be deployed for any organisation using Google Calendar
- Deployed to Google Cloud Run